Sally R. Perez

seattlesally1@gmail.com | (206) 371-2958 | Seattle, WA linkedin.com/in/sallyrperez/ | github.com/SeattleSal | seattlesal.github.io/Portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web developer interested in positions that use my problem-solving mindset and passion to continuously learn new skills. Recently completed the Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from University of Washington and have skills in JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, and a degree in Computer Science. Formerly experienced Technology Auditor so I enjoy continuous learning and am ready to move beyond the focus on analysis to creating valuable solutions.

SKILLS

Javascript, Node JS, Express, jQuery, React JS, React, JSX, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Handlebars, HTML 5, CSS, Heroku

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE | PROJECTS

Neighborhood Cup-O-Sugar | Back End Developer | Deployed: neighborhood-cup-o-sugar.herokuapp.com/ | Github: qithub.com/bfourGitHub/cup-o-sugar

A hyper-local sharing experience for users to give and get free items from neighbors.

Role: Created database models and backend API calls. Integrated with Cloudinary for photo uploads and displays.

Technologies: Javascript, Node, Express, Axios, Bcrypt, passport, mongoose, multer, React, Bootstrap, React-Bootstrap, Cloudinary 3P API

Feast with Friends | Full Stack Developer | Deployed: feast-with-friends-plus.herokuapp.com/ | **GitHub:** github.com/SeattleSal/feast-with-friends

Recommends a list of restaurants that matches the users' dietary restrictions & specified location.

Role: Created mysql models, controllers, back end apis, integration with yelp API, and helped with handlebars.

Technologies: Javascript, Node, axios, bcrypt, passport, handlebars, mysql, sequelize, Yelp 3P API

Trail Chasers | Front End Developer | Deployed: taanibravo.github.io/Trail-Chaser-Hiking-App/ | **GitHub:** github.com/TaaniBravo/Trail-Chaser-Hiking-App

Find hikes based on location, length and difficulty.

Role: Created search and results page using javascript and bulma, made 3P API calls for trail data and google maps data.

Technologies: Javascript, Bulma, Trails and Google Maps 3P APIs

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate, University of Washington, Seattle, WA | March 2021

A 24 week intensive boot camp program focused on gaining technical programming and market-driven skills in Node.js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, React, JSX, GitHub, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Handlebars, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, APIs, Heroku, AJAX, Restful API, ES6, React Hooks, JSON, Sequelize.

Bachelor's in Computer Science, Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ, Graduated Magna Cum Laude

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Manager Tech Audit | Tech Audit Manager, Amazon, Seattle, WA, January 2017 – March 2020

- Headed audit portfolio for Devices, Alexa and Digital Content spaces including Music, Video and Studios. Managed and provided oversight for a team of four.
- Performed end-to-end audit projects over Devices, Alexa, Music, Advertising and InfoSec. Executed test plans over Amazon Web Services (AWS) Identity and Access Management and S3 services.
- Streamlined and built IT General Controls test work programs and training for Internal Audit team.

Senior IT Audit Manager, Outerwall, Bellevue, WA, November 2015 - October 2016

- Operated in house IT Audit function that was formerly outsourced.
- Supported SOX IT work and executed risk-based technology audits.
- Established quality assurance improvement program for Internal Audit activities.

Sally R. Perez

IT Audit Principal, Nordstrom, Seattle, WA, April 2013 – November 2015

- Formed two-year Privacy audit program based on Generally Accepted Privacy Principles. Identified gaps and improvement areas in handling of third-party vendors.
- Executed IT risk assessment and audits over Nordstrom Federal Savings Bank (NFSB) technology environment incorporating guidance from FFIEC IT Handbooks.
- Co-led professional practices initiatives such as continuous process improvement including use of kaizens, benchmarking for best practices and improving communication mechanisms.

Audit Manager | IT Audit Project Manager, Starbucks, Seattle, WA, May 2006 - March 2013

- Provided support and guidance for four direct reports and other team members on projects including compliance audits, operational/financial/IT audits and risk assessments.
- Coordinated reviews in multiple international licensed and joint-venture markets.
- Created system implementation controls self-assessment checklist to proactively address upcoming system implementation reviews, scope future audits and communicate risks with IT stakeholders.
- Led the planning, execution and coordination of a pre-implementation audit review of the largest software implementation in the history of Starbucks at the time. Communicated issues and addressed concerns to external audit team and created communication for executives including the CIO, CFO and Audit Committee.
- Acted as subject matter expert of TeamMate audit software for Internal Audit department. Provided guidance on technical issues and troubleshooting, acted as liaison with IT to roll out installation of new modules, functionality setting and upgrades.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT Security Advisor, Boeing, Seattle, WA

IT Generalist, Boeing, Seattle, WA